Guide to the James Rowland Angell, President of Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
James Rowland Angell, president of Yale University, records
1921-1937
RU 24
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
84.25
The records consist of correspondence, annual reports, memoranda, and subject files documenting James Rowland Angell's activities as president of Yale University. The records contain substantive documentation on virtually every aspect of the university's administration, its schools, departments, and other major units. The files pertaining to the founding of the School of Nursing, the Institute of Human Relations, and the residential colleges are particularly significant.
Yale University. President's Office
Angell, James Rowland, 1869-1949
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 2-A (YRG 2-A), Records of the Yale president's office.
Arrangement
The records are arranged alphabetically by subject.
Scope and Contents
The James Rowland Angell Presidential Papers consist of a single alphabetical sequence of files spanning Angell's entire presidency - 1921-1937. Incoming and outgoing copies of correspondence are filed together, i.e., there is not a separate series of outgoing correspondence carbons in chronological order.
The papers deal with literally every aspect of University activity from 1921 until 1937. See also Mss. Group No. 2, James Rowland Angell Personal Papers.
Biographical / Historical
James Rowland Angell was born on May 8, 1869 in Burlington, Vermont. He attended the University of Michigan (B.A., 1890; M.A., 1891), Harvard (M.A., 1892) and the University of Berlin. From 1893-1919 Angell was a professor of psychology at the University of Chicago and served as acting president from 1918-1919. In 1921 he resigned as president of the Carnegie Corporation to accept the presidency of Yale University, a position he held until 1937. As president of Yale, Angell instituted a major reorganization of the undergraduate curriculum, brought in new faculty, expanded the Graduate School, and increased Yale's stature as a national center of higher education. Major achievements of his administration included the founding of the Yale School of Nursing (1923); the organization of the Institute of Psychology (1924), which was expanded into the Institute of Human Relations (1929); and the adoption of a residential college plan for undergraduates. Angell died in Hamden, Connecticut on March 4, 1949.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Universities and colleges -- Administration; College presidents; Educators; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Presidents; Yale University. Institute of Human Relations; Yale University. President's Office; Yale University. School of Nursing
- Records, 1921-1937; Series I
  - A-Ak (Box 1, Folder 1-5)
  - Adams, Thomas Sewall (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Adee, George T. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Admissions, Board of (Box 1, Folder 8-14)
  - Admissions, Board of (Box 2, Folder 15-16)
  - Admissions, Board of
    - Advanced standing for entering freshmen and new officer (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Advisory Committee to Secondary Schools (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Foreign language requirements (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Increasing number of admissions, 1932-1933 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Individual cases (Box 2, Folder 21-25)
    - Minutes (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Successor to Alan C. Valentine (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - H. Emerson Tuttle (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Alan Chester Valentine (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Al (Box 3, Folder 30-32)
  - Allen, Frederic W. (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Alumni Associations, 1922-1934 (Box 3, Folder 34-42)
  - Alumni Associations, 1935-1937 (Box 4, Folder 43-47)
  - Alumni Associations: New Haven Alumni Association (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Alumni Board (Box 4, Folder 49-51)
  - Alumni Board (Box 5, Folder 52-54)
  - Alumni Board
    - Freshman year: College and Sheffield Scientific School Committee, report on Sheffield Scientific School student councils (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Elton Hoyt, 2nd (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Library Committee (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Ogden D. Miller (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Publicity Committee (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Reorganization Committee (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Sheffield Scientific School Committee (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Yale College Committee (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Yale College and Sheffield Scientific Committee (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Alumni broadcast, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Alumni Fellows: ballots, etc. (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Alumni Fund: College Plan, responses to letter, 1934 January 15 (Box 6, Folder 66-69)
  - Alumni Fund Dinner, 1932 February 21 (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Alumni (University) Fund Association (Box 6, Folder 71-74)
  - Alumni (University) Fund Association (Box 7, Folder 75-76)
  - Alumni in the ministry (Box 7, Folder 77)
  - Alumni interest in reunions, athletic contests, Alumni Fund, etc. (Box 7, Folder 78)
  - Alumni meetings, 1922-1925 (Box 7, Folder 79-82)
  - Alumni meetings, 1935-1937 (Box 7, Folder 83)
  - Alumni occupations, Yale College and Sheffield Scientific School combined (Box 7, Folder 84)
  - Alumni salary statistics (Box 7, Folder 85)
  - Alumni speeches (Box 7, Folder 86)
  - Alumni trips
    - Albany, 1922 February (Box 8, Folder 87)
    - Buffalo, 1921 (Box 8, Folder 88)
    - California and Hawaii, 1934 (Box 8, Folder 89-92)
    - California and Hawaii, University of California: speech (Box 8, Folder 93)
    - Cleveland, 1921 (Box 8, Folder 94)
    - Cleveland, Chicago, St. Louis, 1926 March (Box 8, Folder 95)
    - Detroit, 1922 (Box 8, Folder 96)
    - Essex County, New Jersey, 1922 (Box 8, Folder 97)
    - Fairfield County, Connecticut, 1922 (Box 8, Folder 98)
    - Hartford, 1922 (Box 8, Folder 99)
    - Naugatuck Valley, 1922 (Box 8, Folder 100)
    - Northwest and Chicago Alumni Association, 1924 (Box 8, Folder 101)
    - Oklahoma Yale Club, University of Tulsa, 1922 (Box 8, Folder 102)
    - Philadelphia, 1921 (Box 8, Folder 103)
    - Rhode Island, 1924 (Box 8, Folder 104)
    - Springfield-Western Massachusetts, 1922 (Box 8, Folder 105)
    - Washington, D.C., 1922 (Box 8, Folder 106)
    - Western trip, 1922 (Box 8, Folder 107)
  - Alumni University Day, 1916 (Box 9, Folder 108)
  - Alumni University Day, 1922 (Box 9, Folder 109)
  - Alumni University Day, 1922-1928 (Box 9, Folder 110)
  - Alumni University Day, 1923-1925 (Box 9, Folder 111-114)
  - Alumni University Day, 1929-1933 (Box 9, Folder 115)
  - Alumni University Day, 1934-1935 (Box 9, Folder 116)
  - Alumni University Day, 1936-1937 (Box 9, Folder 117)
  - Am (Box 10, Folder 118-123)
  - Am (Box 11, Folder 124-130)
  - American Association of University Professors (Box 12, Folder 131-132)
  - American Association of University Professors: Committee on College and University Teaching (Box 12, Folder 133-135)
  - American Association of University Women (Box 12, Folder 136)
  - American Bar Association, Washington conference, 1922 February (Box 12, Folder 137)
  - American Council on Education (Box 12, Folder 138-140)
  - American Council on Education (Box 13, Folder 141-145)
  - American Council on Education, Advisory Committee on College Testing Cooperative Test Service (Box 13, Folder 146)
  - American Council on Education, American University Union in Europe (Box 13, Folder 147-148)
  - American Council on Education, American University Union in Europe (Box 14, Folder 149-152)
  - American Journal of Science (Box 14, Folder 153)
  - American Olympic Committee (Box 14, Folder 154)
  - American School of Prehistoric Research (Box 14, Folder 155)
  - American School of Prehistoric Research MacCurdy, George Grant (Box 14, Folder 156)
  - American Social Hygiene Association (Box 14, Folder 157)
  - An (Box 14, Folder 158-160)
  - Angier, Roswell P. (Box 15, Folder 161)
  - Anthropology Department (Box 15, Folder 162)
  - Antioch College (Box 15, Folder 163)
  - Ap-Ar (Box 15, Folder 164-165)
  - Applications for faculty positions at Yale University (Box 15, Folder 166-169)
  - Appointments, Bureau of (Box 15, Folder 170-172)
  - Appointments, Bureau of (Box 16, Folder 173-179)
  - Appointments, Bureau of
    - F.E.R.A., C.W.A., student aid, National Youth Administration (Box 16, Folder 180-181)
    - Graduate Placement Bureau (Box 17, Folder 182-186)
    - Scholarships and fellowships (Box 17, Folder 187)
    - Scholarships, Committee on the General Distribution in the Upper Levels of the University's Work (Box 17, Folder 188)
    - Student employment and scholarship aid situation (Box 17, Folder 189)
  - Architectural Plans Committee (Box 18, Folder 190-192)
  - Architectural Plans Committee
    - Bingham Hall (Box 18, Folder 193)
    - Campus dormitory (Box 18, Folder 194-195)
    - Divinity School (Box 18, Folder 196)
    - Graduate School, 1926-1931 (Box 18, Folder 197)
    - Harkness Educational Building (Dwight Hall) (Box 18, Folder 198)
    - Law School, 1925-1931 (Box 18, Folder 199)
    - Library-York Street dormitory, 1924 (Box 19, Folder 200)
    - Minutes (Box 19, Folder 201-203)
    - Pope Plan for campus buildings, report, 1920 (Box 19, Folder 204)
    - New Sheffield Hall, 1929-1930 (Box 19, Folder 205)
    - President's House, 1922-1924 (Box 19, Folder 206)
    - Sterling Hall of Medicine, 1929-1930 (Box 19, Folder 207)
    - Sterling Memorial Library, 1922-1925 (Box 19, Folder 208-210)
    - Sterling Memorial Library, 1926-1927 (Box 19, Folder 211)
    - Sterling Memorial Library, 1928-1932 (Box 20, Folder 212)
    - Sterling Memorial Library, dedication, 1931 April (Box 20, Folder 213)
  - Aristogenic Association (Box 20, Folder 214)
  - Army R.O.T.C. (Box 20, Folder 215)
  - Art School (Box 20, Folder 216-224)
  - Art School
    - Achelis Collection (Box 21, Folder 225)
    - Art Museum (Box 21, Folder 226)
    - Associates in Fine Arts at Yale (Box 21, Folder 227)
    - Chair in the History of Art (Box 21, Folder 228)
    - Minutes (Box 21, Folder 229)
    - Prix de Rome (Box 21, Folder 230)
  - As (Box 21, Folder 231-233)
  - Association of American Colleges (Box 21, Folder 234-235)
  - Association of American Universities (Box 21, Folder 236-237)
  - Association of American Universities (Box 22, Folder 238-242)
  - Association of Colleges in New England (Box 22, Folder 243-246)
  - Astronomy Department (Box 22, Folder 247)
  - At (Box 23, Folder 248-249)
  - Athletic Association (Box 23, Folder 250-251)
  - Athletic Association
    - Chairman-Director, Committee on (Box 23, Folder 252)
    - Constitution, President's Committee for the Revision of the (Box 23, Folder 253-254)
    - Financial statements (Box 23, Folder 255-256)
    - Financial statements (Box 24, Folder 257-258)
    - Unemployment relief, charity game, 1931-1933 (Box 24, Folder 259-261)
  - Athletic Board of Control (Box 24, Folder 262-267)
  - Athletic Board of Control, Farmer, Malcolm, chairman (Box 25, Folder 268)
  - Athletic Board of Control, minutes (Box 25, Folder 269-274)
  - Athletic Board of Control, nominating committee, 1931 (Box 25, Folder 275)
  - Athletic Club House (Box 25, Folder 276)
  - Athletics
    - Carnegie Foundation, athletic eligibility, proposed study, conferences on (Box 25, Folder 277)
    - Carnegie Foundation, athletic report, Savage, Howard J., 1929-1930 (Box 25, Folder 278)
    - Gates, John M., Athletic Director (Box 25, Folder 279-281)
    - Football (Box 26, Folder 282-285)
    - Football, Army game (Box 26, Folder 286-287)
    - Football coaching, information re other universities (Box 26, Folder 288)
    - Football coaching situation, Alumni Board Executive Committee special meeting (minutes), 1934 January 10 (Box 26, Folder 289)
    - Football coaching situation, telegrams and letters, 1934 January (Box 26, Folder 290)
    - Football, Harvard game (Box 26, Folder 291)
    - Football, Princeton game (Box 26, Folder 292)
    - General (Box 26, Folder 293)
    - General (Box 27, Folder 294-301)
    - General (Box 28, Folder 302-307)
    - Gymnasium administration (Box 28, Folder 308)
    - Hockey (Box 28, Folder 309)
    - Kiphuth, Robert J. (Box 28, Folder 310)
    - Leader, Edward, crew coach (Box 28, Folder 311)
    - National Collegiate Athletic Association (Box 28, Folder 312)
    - National Collegiate Athletic Association (Box 29, Folder 313-314)
    - Nettleton, George H. (Box 29, Folder 315)
    - Payne Whitney Gymnasium Committee (Box 29, Folder 316)
    - Payne Whitney Gymnasium, Ray Tompkins Memorial ( "Y" Club) (Box 29, Folder 317)
    - Payne Whitney University Fund (Box 29, Folder 318)
    - Pond, Raymond W. (Box 29, Folder 319)
    - Root, Reginald D. (Box 29, Folder 320)
    - Rose, R. Selden (Box 29, Folder 321)
    - Rugby Football Club (Box 29, Folder 322)
    - Stevens, Marvin A. (Box 29, Folder 323)
    - Wandle, Frank A., trainer (Box 29, Folder 324)
    - Whitney, John Hay Whitney, Mrs. Payne Payson, Mrs. Charles (Box 29, Folder 325)
    - Woodcock, Harold F. (Box 29, Folder 326)
    - Yale Bowl (Box 29, Folder 327)
    - Yale-Harvard-Princeton agreements (Box 30, Folder 328)
    - Yale-Harvard-Princeton agreements: James B. Conant, Harold Willis Dodd, 1933 (Box 30, Folder 329)
    - Yale-Harvard-Princeton agreements: minutes, press releases (Box 30, Folder 330)
    - Yale-Harvard-Princeton meeting, New York, 1922 March 8 (Box 30, Folder 331-332)
    - Yale-Harvard-Princeton: opening dates for football practice (Box 30, Folder 333)
  - Au-Az (Box 30, Folder 334)
  - Aurelian Society (Box 30, Folder 335)
  - Avery, Myra (Box 30, Folder 336)
  - Aviation (Box 30, Folder 337)
  - Ba (Box 31, Folder 338)
  - Baccalaureate (Box 31, Folder 339)
  - Bacon, Benjamin W., Exploration, Asia Minor-Sir William Ramsey and Mr. Whitehead (Box 31, Folder 340)
  - Bak (Box 31, Folder 341)
  - Baker (Judge) Foundation (Box 31, Folder 342)
  - Baker, Newton D. (Box 31, Folder 343)
  - Bakewell, Charles M. (Box 31, Folder 344)
  - Banking and Foreign Exchange, (Ernest, Fox and Crane proposal, re establishment of chair endowment) (Box 31, Folder 345)
  - Bannard, Otto T. (Box 31, Folder 346)
  - Banner and Pot-Pourri (Box 31, Folder 347)
  - Bar (Box 31, Folder 348-349)
  - Barnum, William M. (Box 31, Folder 350)
  - Barton, Clarence E. estate (Box 31, Folder 351)
  - Bas (Box 31, Folder 352)
  - Baudisch, Dr. Oskar (Box 31, Folder 353)
  - Be (Box 32, Folder 354)
  - Beard, Augustus F., D.D. Rev. (Box 32, Folder 355)
  - Belding, Edgar F. Fund (Box 32, Folder 356)
  - Ben (Box 32, Folder 357)
  - Bequests proposed, wills being drawn, etc. (Box 32, Folder 358)
  - Ber (Box 32, Folder 359)
  - Berkeley Divinity School (Box 32, Folder 360)
  - Berzelius Society (Box 32, Folder 361)
  - Bi (Box 32, Folder 362)
  - Bingham, Hiram (Box 32, Folder 363)
  - Bingham, W.V. (Box 32, Folder 364)
  - Birth control (Box 32, Folder 365)
  - Bishop Museum (Box 33, Folder 366-367)
  - Bishop Museum and H.E. Gregory (Box 33, Folder 368)
  - Bishop Museum, Committee on Relations with University of Hawaii (Box 33, Folder 369-370)
  - Bl (Box 34, Folder 371)
  - Blakeslee, Clarence (Box 34, Folder 372)
  - Block Foundation (Box 34, Folder 373)
  - Bo (Box 34, Folder 374)
  - Board, Samuel S. (Box 34, Folder 375)
  - Bonn, Moritz (Box 34, Folder 376)
  - Bookman Foundation (Box 34, Folder 377)
  - Bor (Box 34, Folder 378)
  - Bos (Box 34, Folder 379)
  - Boston Yale Club (Box 34, Folder 380)
  - Botany, Department of (Box 35, Folder 381)
  - Bowdoin College (Box 35, Folder 382)
  - Bra (Box 35, Folder 383)
  - Bradford, Arthur H. (Box 35, Folder 384)
  - Brewster, Chauncey B. (Box 35, Folder 385)
  - Bri (Box 35, Folder 386)
  - Bristol and White (Box 35, Folder 387)
  - Bristol and White, Committees Re Tax: City Committee and University Committee (Box 35, Folder 388-389)
  - Bristol and White, Committees Re Tax: City Committee and University Committee (Box 36, Folder 390-392)
  - Bristol and White, Taxation correspondence (Box 36, Folder 393-396)
  - Bristol and White, Taxation problem Harvard Taxation letters, etc. (Box 37, Folder 397-398)
  - Bro (Box 37, Folder 399-400)
  - Brooks-Aten, Mrs. (Donor of the Brooks-Bright Foundation) (Box 37, Folder 401)
  - Brooks-Bright Foundation (Formerly Brooks-Bryce Foundation) (Box 37, Folder 402-404)
  - Brouha, Lucien (Box 38, Folder 405)
  - Brown, Charles R. Dean (Box 38, Folder 406)
  - Brown, Ernest W., Professor History of Science Library (Box 38, Folder 407)
  - Brown, William Adams (Box 38, Folder 408)
  - Brown University (Box 38, Folder 409)
  - Bryn Mawr (Box 38, Folder 410)
  - Bu (Box 38, Folder 411)
  - Buckner, Mortimer (Box 38, Folder 412)
  - Budget (Box 38, Folder 413-414)
  - Budget (Box 39, Folder 415-416)
  - Building Committee (Box 39, Folder 417-419)
  - Building lines (Box 39, Folder 420)
  - Building-stone (Box 39, Folder 421)
  - Buildings, miscellaneous memos (Box 39, Folder 422)
  - Bulkley, Mrs. Jonathan (Box 39, Folder 423)
  - Bur-By (Box 39, Folder 424)
  - C (Box 40, Folder 425)
  - Calendar (Box 40, Folder 426)
  - Calendar, University (proposed changes) (Box 40, Folder 427)
  - Calhoun, Newell M. (Box 40, Folder 428)
  - California, University of (Box 40, Folder 429)
  - Cambridge-Oxford Applications, Committee to Act on (Box 40, Folder 430)
  - Camp, Walter, Memorial Service (Box 40, Folder 431)
  - Canby, Henry S. ( Saturday Review ) (Box 40, Folder 432)
  - Car (Box 40, Folder 433-435)
  - Carnegie Corporation, 522 Fifth Avenue, F.P. Keppel, President (Box 41, Folder 436-437)
  - Carnegie Foundation for Advancement of Teaching, Pensions, etc. (Box 41, Folder 438-439)
  - Carnegie Foundation, Teachers' Insurance and Annuity Association of America (Box 41, Folder 440)
  - Carnegie Institution at Washington (Box 41, Folder 441)
  - Carty, General John J. (Box 41, Folder 442)
  - Gas (Box 42, Folder 443)
  - Catalogues, Yale (Box 42, Folder 444)
  - Catholic, Roman (Box 42, Folder 445)
  - Ch (Box 42, Folder 446-447)
  - Chapel (Box 42, Folder 448-449)
  - Chapel
    - Reverend Sidney Lovett (Box 42, Folder 450)
    - Reinhold Niebuhr (Box 42, Folder 451)
    - Canon Raven (Box 42, Folder 452)
    - Services, Committee on Department of Religion (Corporation and Faculty), 1926-1928 (Box 42, Folder 453-454)
    - Richard R. Smith, Inc., Publishers (Charles W. Ferguson) Sermon address of President Angell (Box 43, Folder 455)
    - Sunday: Upperclassmen and Freshmen (Box 43, Folder 456-457)
    - Committee on Chaplain-Pastor (Box 43, Folder 458)
    - Committee on Department of Religion, Professor of Religion-new appointment (Box 43, Folder 459)
    - Committee on Religious Life at the University (Box 43, Folder 460)
  - Chapman, John J. (Box 43, Folder 461)
  - Charlety, Sabastien Recteur (Box 43, Folder 462)
  - Chemical Foundation (Box 43, Folder 463)
  - Chemical Industry Protection (Box 43, Folder 464)
  - Chemistry Department (Box 43, Folder 465-467)
  - Chemistry Department, Chairmen (Box 43, Folder 468)
  - Chemistry Department, obscene postcard (Box 43, Folder 469)
  - Chemistry Laboratory, Sterling (Dedication) (Box 44, Folder 470-471)
  - Cheney, Howell (Box 44, Folder 472)
  - Cheney Fellowship in Organic Chemistry (Box 44, Folder 473)
  - Chi (Box 44, Folder 474-475)
  - Chicago Doctors (Box 44, Folder 476)
  - Chicago, University of (Box 45, Folder 477-478)
  - Child Welfare League of America, Inc. (Box 45, Folder 479)
  - Chinese Exhibition, 1924 (Box 45, Folder 480)
  - Chittenden, Russell H. (Box 45, Folder 481)
  - Ci (Box 45, Folder 482-483)
  - Cincinnati, Society of the (Box 45, Folder 484)
  - Clark, Charles Hopkins (Box 45, Folder 485)
  - Class of 1890, Yale College (Box 46, Folder 486)
  - Class Reunions, Committee on Liquor at Commencement, etc. (Box 46, Folder 487)
  - Class Secretaries Association (Box 46, Folder 488)
  - Class size-college level, Earl Hudelson (Box 46, Folder 489)
  - Classes, Dinners, Records, etc. (Box 46, Folder 490-492)
  - Classical Department (Box 46, Folder 493-494)
  - Classical Survey, Dean West (Box 46, Folder 495)
  - Clement Prize Fund (Box 47, Folder 496)
  - Clerical Assistance (Box 47, Folder 497)
  - Co (Box 47, Folder 498)
  - Coffin, Henry Sloane (Box 47, Folder 499)
  - Col (Box 47, Folder 500-502)
  - Coleman, John Jr. (Box 47, Folder 503)
  - College Hygiene, President's Committee of Fifty on (Box 47, Folder 504)
  - Columbia University (Box 47, Folder 505-506)
  - Commencement, 1922-1930 (Box 48, Folder 507-515)
  - Commencement, 1931-1934 (Box 49, Folder 516-519)
  - Commencement, 1935-1937 (Box 50, Folder 520-522)
  - Commencement Academic Costume (Box 50, Folder 523)
  - Commission for Relief in Belgium, (C.R.B.) Educational Foundation, Inc. (Box 51, Folder 524-525)
  - Commonwealth Fund-Educational Research, Committee Appropriations for Yale (Box 51, Folder 526)
  - Commonwealth Fund Fellowships (Box 51, Folder 527)
  - Con (Box 51, Folder 528-529)
  - Con (Box 52, Folder 530)
  - Connecticut Department of Education (Box 52, Folder 531)
  - Connecticut Geological and Natural History Survey (Box 52, Folder 532)
  - Connecticut Junior College (Box 52, Folder 533)
  - Connecticut Unemployment Commission (Box 52, Folder 534)
  - Connfelt, Oscar G. (Box 52, Folder 535)
  - Coolidge, Mrs. F.S. (Box 52, Folder 536)
  - Copley, I.C. (Box 52, Folder 537)
  - Copyright, International (Box 52, Folder 538-539)
  - Cor (Box 53, Folder 540)
  - Corporation (General folder) (Box 53, Folder 541)
  - Corporation and Faculty, Committee to Consider Cosmopolitan Club Proposal for Foreign Students (Box 53, Folder 542)
  - Corporation By-Laws (Box 53, Folder 543-544)
  - Corporation Committee Appointed to Study the Operating Costs of the University, Report on Control of University's Portfolio (Box 54, Folder 545)
  - Corporation Committee
    - Board of Athletics Budget (Box 54, Folder 546)
    - Law School Budget (Box 54, Folder 547)
    - Library Budget (Box 54, Folder 548)
    - Medical School Budget (Box 54, Folder 549)
  - Corporation Committee on
    - Educational Costs (Graves Committee) (Box 54, Folder 550-553)
    - Educational Costs (Graves Committee), JRA letter to Yale Daily News (Box 54, Folder 554)
    - Educational Costs (Graves Committee), Preliminary Report (extra copies), 1936 April 14 (Box 54, Folder 555)
    - The Presidency (Box 54, Folder 556)
  - Corporation Committees and Members (Box 54, Folder 557)
  - Corporation, Successors to the original Trustees (Box 55, Folder 558-559)
  - Corporation, Votes, etc. (Box 55, Folder 560)
  - Corwin, Robert N. (Box 55, Folder 561)
  - Cosmopolitan Club (Box 55, Folder 562)
  - Council, University (Box 55, Folder 563)
  - Course of Study-Clive Day (Box 55, Folder 564-566)
  - Cowles-Stewart, William H. and Alfred Cowles, Philip Stewart (Box 56, Folder 567-568)
  - Coxe, Mrs. Alexander. Brown (Box 56, Folder 569)
  - Cr (Box 56, Folder 570)
  - Cranks (Box 56, Folder 571)
  - Cross, Wilbur L. (Box 56, Folder 572)
  - Cu (Box 56, Folder 573)
  - Gushing, Harvey, Dr. (Box 56, Folder 574)
  - Cuyler, Thomas Dewitt Memorial, Professorship of Transportation (Box 56, Folder 575)
  - Cycles, Current Budget Material, 1923-1924 (Box 56, Folder 576)
  - Da (Box 57, Folder 577)
  - Danford, Robert M. (Box 57, Folder 578)
  - Dante Celebration (Box 57, Folder 579)
  - Dartmouth College, President E.M. Hopkins (Box 57, Folder 580-584)
  - Dav-Daz (General correspondence) (Box 57, Folder 585)
  - Davis, Jerome (Box 57, Folder 586-587)
  - Davis, Jerome
    - American Association of University Professors, Investigating Committee (Box 58, Folder 588-590)
    - American Federation of Teachers, Final Report, 1937 May (Box 58, Folder 591)
    - Bliven Letter (copies) (Box 58, Folder 592)
    - Bulletin of the American Association of University Professors, 1936 Feb, 1937 May (Box 58, Folder 593)
    - Corporation and Faculty re: votes and correspondence (Box 58, Folder 594)